<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<fp xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
	<row>
		<rowno>41</rowno>
		<id>CP.1.1</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>8</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to capture structured data in the patient history (e.g., administrative, social, mental health, geographic location, and/or financial statuses, poverty, orphan, disability, incarceration, incompetence, or remote geographic location). Dental Note: Community fluoridation is an example.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>44</rowno>
		<id>CP.1.1</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>11</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHOULD provide the ability to capture patient history adhering to a standards-based form or template according to scope of practice, organizational policy, and/or jurisdictional law. Dental Note: May be implemented through a patient portal, secure messaging, or a Progress Note.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>103</rowno>
		<id>CP.1.3</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>28</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to render active medications and materials as defined by user requirements and according to scope of practice, organizational policy, and/or jurisdictional law (e.g., including medications that may still have a physiologic effect long after last administration).</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>108</rowno>
		<id>CP.1.4</id>
		<type>F</type>
		<statement>Create and maintain patient-specific problem lists.  </statement>
		<description>A problem list may include, but is not limited to chronic conditions, diagnoses, or symptoms, injury/poisoning (both intentional and unintentional), adverse effects of medical or dental care (e.g., drugs, surgical), functional limitations, visit or stay-specific conditions, diagnoses, or symptoms. When a dentist creates a problem list, that list will focus on conditions clinically relevant to oral health care.  Problem lists are managed over time, whether over the course of a visit or stay or the life of a patient, allowing documentation of historical information and tracking the changing character of problem(s) and their priority. The source (e.g., the provider, the system id, or the patient) of the updates should be documented. All pertinent dates are stored, including date noted or diagnosed, dates of any changes in problem specification or prioritization, and date of resolution. This might include time stamps, where useful and appropriate. The entire problem history for any problem in the list is viewable.  For dentistry, only a limited medical history is often recorded; however, this limited medical history must not be represented as a comprehensive medical history.  </description>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>109</rowno>
		<id>CP.1.4</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>1</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to manage, as discrete data, all active problems associated with a patient, including all active problems associated with the oral health of a patient.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>110</rowno>
		<id>CP.1.4</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>2</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL capture, maintain and render a history of all problems associated with a patient.   For dental care, the entire problem history may only include problems that are provider-defined as relevant to oral health care.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>145</rowno>
		<id>CP.1.6</id>
		<type>F</type>
		<statement>Create and maintain patient-specific immunization lists. </statement>
		<description>Immunization lists are managed over time, whether over the course of a visit or stay, or the lifetime of a patient. Details of immunizations administered are captured as discrete data elements including date, type, manufacturer and lot number. The entire immunization history is viewable. Dental Note: Immunizations by dental providers may become more important as states are starting to compel them by law. There are still questions as to whether or not dental practices will need to be able to track immunizations.  </description>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>164</rowno>
		<id>CP.1.8</id>
		<type>F</type>
		<statement>Capture and maintain patient and family preferences.</statement>
		<description>This function is focused on the capture and maintenance of facts on patient/family preferences. Patient and family preferences regarding issues such as language, religion, spiritual practices and culture may be important to the delivery of care. It is important to capture these so that they will be available to the provider at the point of care. Patient/Family preferences differ from social history and Advance Directives as follows: Social history refers primarily to elements of a patient's background that may impact on the patient's health (e.g., smoking, drinking, occupation, abuse, etc.). Advance Directives refers to requests regarding care when the patient is unable to competently make decisions about their own care (e.g., Do Not Resuscitate orders, living wills). For Dental, this applies to a dental patient treated in hospital, where the DNR must be documented in chart for the hospital admission.</description>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>170</rowno>
		<id>CP.1.9</id>
		<type>F</type>
		<statement>Capture and maintain adverse events.</statement>
		<description>This function is focused on the capture and maintenance of adverse events that have occurred to the patient. The system should capture discrete information about the adverse event to enable the rendering Serious Adverse Event (SAE) reports according to organizational policy, and or jurisdictional law. Reporting may conform to the HL7 Individual Case Safety Reporting (ICSR). For Dental, the HL7 Individual Case Safety Report (ICSR) captures information needed to support reporting of adverse events, product problems and consumer complaints associated with the use of FDA regulated products. Examples include Biologics and Vaccines Adverse Events, Food Adverse Events, Human Drugs Adverse Events, Medical Device Adverse Events, and Tobacco Adverse Events.</description>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>179</rowno>
		<id>CP.2.2</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>1</cc>
		<criteria>IF the system conforms to function [[CPS.2.2]] (Support for externally-sourced Clinical data), THEN the system SHALL provide the ability to render externally-sourced clinical data. Dental Examples include bar code scanning of products, implants, and medications, such as epi pen, including lot number and expiration date per FDA regulations.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>184</rowno>
		<id>CP.2.5</id>
		<type>F</type>
		<statement>Capture and explicitly label patient-originated data, link the data source with the data, and support provider authentication for inclusion in patient health record as well as subsequent rendering of the information as part of the health record.</statement>
		<description>It is critically important to be able to distinguish clinically authored and authenticated data from patient-originated data that is either provided by the patient for inclusion in the EHR or entered directly into the EHR by the patient from clinically authenticated data. Patients may provide data for entry into the health record or be given a mechanism for entering this data directly. Patient-originated data intended for use by providers will be available for their use. Dental Note: Include date and time of acquisition and entry into record. Dental examples include consumer healthcare devices, CPAP for sleep apnea, products, including patient-provided info regarding medications the patient has taken, and saliva samples provided for commercial genetic analysis.
Data about the patient may be appropriately provided by:
- the patient;
- a surrogate (parent, spouse, guardian) or 
- an informant (teacher, lawyer, case worker) 
- devices (e.g., blood pressure/sugar monitors). 
An electronic health record may provide the ability for direct data entry by any of these. Patient-originated data may also be captured by devices and transmitted for inclusion into the electronic health record.
Data entered by any of these must be stored with source information. A provider must authenticate patient-originated data included in the patient's legal health record. A provider must be able to indicate they have verified the accuracy of patient-originated data (when appropriate and when a verification source is available) for inclusion in the patient record. Such verification does not have to occur at each individual data field and can be at a higher level of the data.</description>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>185</rowno>
		<id>CP.2.5</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>1</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to capture patient-originated data and tag that data as such. Dental Note: Include date and time of acquisition and entry into record.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>268</rowno>
		<id>CP.3.4</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>15</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to capture, maintain and render, as discrete data, the reason for variation from rule-based clinical messages (e.g., alerts and reminders). Dental Example: Military requires note when rubber dam is not used, and this could require a specific data field.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>335</rowno>
		<id>CP.4.2</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>15</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to determine and render the status of a medication order (e.g., for outpatient medication ordering: captured, verified, filled, or dispensed to patient; for inpatient: captured, verified, filled, or medication administered). For Dental, this could be in a Progress Note.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>337</rowno>
		<id>CP.4.2</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>17</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL conform to function [[CP.1.3]] (Manage Medication List) and update the appropriate medication list with the prescribed medications (in case of multiple medication lists). Dental Note: This could be a discreet medication list or could be a medication list elaborated in a Progress Note. Medication reconciliation is the goal and the method will vary.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>338</rowno>
		<id>CP.4.2</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>18</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to enter and maintain medication information supplied by the patient. Dental Note: This could be a discreet medication list or could be a medication list elaborated in a Progress Note. Medication reconciliation is the goal and the method will vary.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>346</rowno>
		<id>CP.4.2</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>26</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to capture, maintain, and render an order for supplies that are associated with medication orders according to scope of practice, organizational policy, and/or jurisdictional law. Dental Note: Examples include needles for insulin, dental lab orders, restorative materials, bone graft materials, size of needles (length and gauge), and supplies only for professional use and purchase.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>357</rowno>
		<id>CP.4.2</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>37</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL track the number of times that a prescription was transmitted (to maintain a constraint on the number of times that a prescription is permitted to be transmitted for printing/reprinting and faxing/re-faxing). Dental Note: System should have feedback loop for Rx transmitted to pharmacy. Written Rx tracking will be noted in Rx Package in EDR or in Progress Note. </criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>367</rowno>
		<id>CP.4.2.1</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>1</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL conform to function [[CPS.4.2.1]] (Support for Medication Interaction and Allergy Checking) to determine allergic reactions, drug-drug interactions, and other potential adverse reactions, and render alerts or notifications when new medications are ordered. Dental Note: According to scope of practice, organizational policy, and/or jurisdictional law, can be, but is not limited to, an API to Rx module. Could also be entered manually and then cross-checked manually.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>368</rowno>
		<id>CP.4.2.1</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>2</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL conform to function [[CP.1.2]] (Manage Allergy, Intolerance and Adverse Reaction List) to provide the ability to manage interaction and allergy checking and render alerts and notifications when new medications are ordered. Dental Note: According to scope of practice, organizational policy, and/or jurisdictional law, can be, but is not limited to, an API to Rx module. Could also be entered manually and then cross-checked manually.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>373</rowno>
		<id>CP.4.2.2</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>1</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL conform to function [[CPS.4.2.2]] (Support for Patient-Specific Dosing and Warnings) to determine potential adverse reactions and render alerts or notifications when new medications are ordered. Dental Note: According to scope of practice, organizational policy, and/or jurisdictional law, can be, but is not limited to, an API to Rx module. Could also be entered manually and then cross-checked manually.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>400</rowno>
		<id>CP.4.3</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>1</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to manage non-medication patient care orders for an action or item. Dental Note: Includes smoking cessation counseling and dietary orders.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>422</rowno>
		<id>CP.4.5</id>
		<type>F</type>
		<statement>Communicate with appropriate sources or registries to manage orders for blood products or other biologics.</statement>
		<description>Interact with a blood bank system or other source to support orders for blood products or other biologics including discontinuance orders. Use of such products in the provision of care is captured. Blood bank or other functionality that may come under jurisdictional law or other regulation (e.g., by the FDA in the United States) is not required; functional communication with such a system is required. Dental examples include platelet rich plasma, fresh frozen plasma administered prior to extraction, and bone grafting materials.</description>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>426</rowno>
		<id>CP.4.5</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>4</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to manage the status of storage request orders (e.g., requisitioned, completed, in process) for blood products, and/or biological products. Dental Note: This includes any tissue-derived products, including autografts.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>428</rowno>
		<id>CP.4.5</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>6</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to manage the use of blood products and other biologics in the provision of care. Dental Note: These products include any tissue-derived products, including autografts, as well as the barcode tracking of kits used to obtain autologous graft samples from a patient.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>493</rowno>
		<id>CP.6.1</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>11</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to capture, maintain, and render medication administration details as discrete data, according to scope of practice, organizational policy, and/or jurisdictional law, including:
- the medication name, including generic names and associated trade names, such as Arestin, oxycodone, penicillin, etc., from a reference library, i.e., "mineable data," with strength and dose;
- date and time of administration;
- route and site;
- administering provider;
- observations, reactions and complications;
- reason medication not given and/or medication related activity not performed.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>509</rowno>
		<id>CP.6.1</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>27</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to capture and render patient-specific instructions or other free text related to the administration of the medication (e.g., use left-arm IV only). For Dental, SHALL also include the ability to capture and render patient-specific documentation and instructions or directions for off-label uses.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>524</rowno>
		<id>CP.6.2</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>1</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to capture immunization administration details as discrete data, including: (1) the immunization name/type, series, strength and dose; (2) date and time of administration; (3) manufacturer, lot number, expiration date; (4) route and site of administration; (5) administering provider; (6) observations, reactions and complications; (7) reason immunization not given, and/or immunization related activity not performed; according to scope of practice, organizational policy, and/or jurisdictional law. For Dental, SHALL be able to capture, send, and receive this info in the dental record according to scope of practice, organizational policy, and/or jurisdictional law, including public health situations.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>526</rowno>
		<id>CP.6.2</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>3</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to determine and render required immunizations, and when they are due, based on widely accepted immunization schedules, when rendering encounter information. For Dental, this SHALL apply for states allowing this in the dental office and SHALL provide bi-directional exchange according to scope of practice, organizational policy, and/or jurisdictional law, including public health situations. </criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>530</rowno>
		<id>CP.6.2</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>7</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to maintain a patient-specific immunization schedule. For Dental, this SHALL be bi-directional according to scope of practice, organizational policy, and/or jurisdictional law.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>586</rowno>
		<id>CP.7.1</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>3</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to render previously used guidelines and protocols for historical or legal purposes. For Dental, examples of professional care guidelines include periodontal disease guidelines or caries disease guidelines.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>592</rowno>
		<id>CP.7.2</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>3</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to render an alert of the recommendation based on the date associated with the recommendation (e.g., if recommendation is to 'book appointment for physical therapy in 2 weeks' - alert will be triggered in 1.5 weeks for follow-up). Dental Note: Some dental electronic records currently support this function.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>627</rowno>
		<id>CPS.1.1</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>3</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to manage a record for a patient when the identity of the patient is unknown. Dental Example: Dental EDR can assign a unique identifier for a situation where there is incomplete patient info for ID.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>629</rowno>
		<id>CPS.1.1</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>5</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to manage more than one patient identifier for each patient record. For Dental, this could be among different record systems (e.g., EDR, imaging) or could be multiple IDs for patient matching among EMR and EDR systems.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>701</rowno>
		<id>CPS.1.5</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>7</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to capture one or more complaints, presenting problems, or other reasons for the visit or encounter (e.g., chest pain, gunshot wound, and drug overdose during a single encounter). Dental examples include dental pain, swelling, bleeding, trauma, infection, and malocclusion. </criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>702</rowno>
		<id>CPS.1.5</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>8</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to capture the primary reason (e.g., the Chief Complaint or the most important reason) for visit/encounter from the patient's perspective. Dental examples include dental pain, swelling, bleeding, trauma, infection, and malocclusion. </criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>710</rowno>
		<id>CPS.1.6.2</id>
		<type>F</type>
		<statement>Support interactions with other systems, applications, and modules to provide information on an insured person's relationships. Examples of relationships include domestic partner, spouse, and guarantor of payment. Dental examples include parent, children, caregiver, and legal guardian.</statement>
		<description>Identifying relationship of persons insured under the same insurance plan is important for administrative transactions.</description>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>712</rowno>
		<id>CPS.1.6.3</id>
		<type>F</type>
		<statement>Provide information on relationships by living situation. Examples of living situations include college dormitory, military deployment, in same household. Dental examples includes homeless, prison, basic training barracks, large housing facilities, and  cruise ships</statement>
		<description>Living situations may be important means for providers to uniquely identify patients or to identify illnesses that may occur within a given proximity. Patient relationships that may be affected by past situations may include the environment of the patient when the patient was a fetus, for example, a mother who worked in a chemical factory last week or while pregnant with the patient thirty years prior, or mother carried child during time of extreme famine.</description>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>721</rowno>
		<id>CPS.1.7.1</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>1</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to capture, maintain and render patient and family preferences as they pertain to current treatment plans. Dental examples include no amalgam, allergic to "Novocain," and parents only speak Ukrainian.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>779</rowno>
		<id>CPS.2.4</id>
		<type>F</type>
		<statement>Incorporate clinical images from external sources and support communication/presentation of images from medical and non-medical devices and entities. Dental could use APIs to accomplish this.</statement>
		<description>Mechanisms for incorporating external clinical images (including identification of source) are available and communication with non-medical devices and entities is supported as appropriate to the care setting such as an office or a patient's home. Externally-sourced images may be presented with locally-sourced documentation and notes wherever appropriate. This covers all types of images received by the provider that would typically be incorporated into a medical record. These image documents are indexed and can be retrieved, e.g., based on the document type, date of the original document, and the date of scanning. Images may also be stored within the system or accessed by reference to an external system (e.g., a hospital's picture archiving and communication system). Examples of image formats include OCR, PDF, JPG, or TIFF.
Examples of externally-sourced images include: 
- Laboratory results report images;
- Radiographic images;
- Images of power of attorney forms, living wills or birth certificates;
- Graphs and charts;
- Photographs or drawings of a patient's wounds;
- Wave files of EKG tracings.</description>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>807</rowno>
		<id>CPS.3.1</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>1</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to capture, maintain, and render recognized-standard assessment information in the patient record. Dental examples include PreViser and CAMBRA risk assessments, and health history.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>840</rowno>
		<id>CPS.3.4</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>1</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to render care and treatment plans that are sensitive to the context of patient data and assessments. Dental treatment plan examples include pediatric vs. adult, ortho, and perio.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>869</rowno>
		<id>CPS.3.8</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>1</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to capture that clinical decision support prompts have been rendered and user response to accept or override those prompts. In dental electronic records, a Prompt is usually called an "Alert." Dental examples include allergies, a pre-med requirement, or Rx opioid use.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>870</rowno>
		<id>CPS.3.8</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>2</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to capture the reason for variation from the decision support prompt. For Dental, the reason could be documented in a progress note.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>878</rowno>
		<id>CPS.3.10</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>1</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL conform to function [[CP.3.1]] (Conduct Assessments) and provide the ability to access standard assessment data in the patient record. Dental example is exacerbation of a stable perio status.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>911</rowno>
		<id>CPS.4</id>
		<type>F</type>
		<statement>Support for Orders is required to ensure that appropriate decision support and safety checks are conducted by the system at the time of ordering as well as at the time of dispensing medications or immunizations.</statement>
		<description>Support for orders includes the management of order set templates, the support for specific types of orders including medication, immunization, non-medication, diagnostic tests as well as blood products and biologicals. Decision Support for orders includes checking for allergies or adverse interactions, dosing checking and issuing the appropriate warnings. It may also include functions to increase ordering efficiency such as verifying all necessary information to fulfill the order is captured and making recommendations for supporting orders. A component of ordering medications and immunizations is the dispensing of those orders and, where applicable, this function will include criteria to support dispensing. Note: Administration of Orders is included in [[CPS.6]] (Support for Treatment Administration). For Dental, these requirements are based on the scope of practice, practice context, preferred standards, provider preferences, organizational policy, or other applicable criteria. This approach for Dental applies throughout CPS 4.</description>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>1059</rowno>
		<id>CPS.5</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>1</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL render alerts for a result that is outside of a normal value range. Current Dental examples include high risk assessments for caries or perio, culture and sensitivity tests, and blood tests. Patient could bring results and dental provider then enters into EDR or the results could come electronically.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>1064</rowno>
		<id>CPS.5</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>6</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL tag critical value results that have not been acknowledged. Current Dental examples include high risk assessments for caries or perio, culture and sensitivity tests, and blood tests. Dental patient could bring results and dental provider enters into EDR or the results could come electronically.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>1070</rowno>
		<id>CPS.6.1</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>1</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL determine and render notifications regarding potential administration errors such as wrong patient, wrong drug, wrong dose, wrong route and wrong time as it relates to medication administration at the point of medication administration. Dental Note: This is primarily administration of medications or blood products in the surgical outpatient office or in the hospital, not outpatient medications through prescription. This function will usually be present in the institutional record, not in the electronic dental record (EDR). If applied to dentistry, this workflow should usually leverage the electronic medical record, not the EDR. This approach also pertains to medication or immunization orders in the dental office. </criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>1098</rowno>
		<id>CPS.6.4</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>1</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to render information necessary to correctly identify the patient and accurately identify the specimen to be collected including, but not limited to, patient name, specimen type, specimen source, means of collection, date and time. For Dental, bar coding could be supported.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>1104</rowno>
		<id>CPS.7.1</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>1</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to render external evidence-based healthcare recommendations, including documentation of sources. Dental examples include perio maintenance, recalls, caries management (fluoride varnish), etc.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>1358</rowno>
		<id>POP.6.4</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>1</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL provide the ability to manage at least one data-driven feedback mechanism (e.g., reports, dashboards, or watchboards) to assist in patient management and healthcare delivery. For Dental, this includes Quality information.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>1565</rowno>
		<id>AS.5.4</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>12</cc>
		<criteria>IF the system provides the ability to determine when time limits for a particular task are exceeded, THEN the system SHALL provide the ability to render a list of these tasks.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
	<row>
		<rowno>1586</rowno>
		<id>AS.6.4</id>
		<type>C</type>
		<cc>2</cc>
		<criteria>The system SHALL capture, maintain and render triage acuity ratings derived from standardized acuity scales. For Dental, this may include dental status for military readiness for deployment.</criteria>
		<changeindicator>C</changeindicator>
	</row>
</fp>